Guide to the Jean Witter Papers, 1953-2007 AIS.2008.06
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Jean Witter Papers
1953-2007
1965-1984
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Witter, Jean
AIS.2008.06
13 Linear Feet (10 records center boxes, 1 photograph box)
This collection documents the activism of Jean Witter, a Pittsburgh lawyer, who was heavily involved with the National Organization for Women (NOW) and an advocate for the passage of the Equal Rights Amendment. This collection contains correspondence, meeting minutes, promotional material, personal notes and writings, and ephemera related to the women's rights movement.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Raymond and David Witter on August 5, 2008.
Scope and Content Notes
The Jean Witter Papers include correspondence, legislative material relating to the Equal Rights Amendment, meeting minutes and organizational information on the National Organization for Women (specifically the Pittsburgh chapter), promotional material for both the ERA and NOW, personal records, a sampling of articles and notes on general women's issues, Witter's personal writings (both notes and essays), and ephemeral material relating to the women's rights movement. The primary focus of the collection is on Witter's involvement in NOW and the foundations of the Pittsburgh chapter, and her work on the passage of the ERA. The collection also contains several audio cassettes, which include speeches and interviews given by Witter, as well as material relating to the overall movement for equality for women.
Previous Citation
Jean Witter Papers, 1953-2007, AIS.2008.06, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Biography
Jean Witter was born Jean Peindl on July 23, 1927, and was raised in the South Hills of Pittsburgh. She earned a degree in crystallography from Duquesne University during World War II, which was rather rare for the time period. She worked as a chemical librarian until she was able to get a research position at the University of Pittsburgh. She married DuWayne Witter and had two sons.
During the 1960s, Witter became interested in the women's rights movement, and became one of the first presidents of the Pittsburgh chapter of the National Organization for Women (NOW). She was interested primarily in the passage of the Equal Rights Amendment (ERA), and was appointed Chairperson for NOW's ERA Committee. In order to strengthen her arguments and credibility, Witter attended law school at Duquesne in the early 1970s. After passing the bar exam, Witter threw herself into promoting the ratification of the ERA. One of her most significant contributions to the campaign was a legal opinion she authored that prompted Congress to extend the deadline for ratification by three years. After the ERA failed to pass, Witter still remained active as a lawyer, mostly by advocating women's issues, particularly in regards to sexual discrimination and equal employment rights.
Witter passed away in 2008, at the age of 80.
Social action; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Personal papers; Women's studies -- United States; Women; Feminists -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Feminism -- United States; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States; Equal rights amendments -- United States; Women's rights -- United States; National Organization for Women. Pittsburgh Chapter; National Organization for Women. Pennsylvania Chapter; National Organization for Women; Judd Hill, Cindy; Evansgardner, JoAnn; Schlafly, Phyllis; Heide, Wilma Scott; Witter, Jean
- Correspondence, 1953-2003; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Series I consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence for the years 1953 through 2003. The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by subject/correspondent, and chronologically within each subject.
  - Heide, Wilma Scott, 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Heide, Wilma Scott, 1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Kestner-Lang, Carol Anne, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Kestner-Lang, Carol Anne, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Kestner-Lang, Carol Anne, 1986-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General, 1953-1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Women's Issues, 1968-2003, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Equal Rights Amendment, 1966-2007; II.
  Series II consists of materials relating to the attempts to ratify the Equal Rights Amendment (ERA), a cause which Witter was heavily involved in. This series includes promotional material, legislative material, memos, newsletters, correspondence, notes, and reports. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Ad-Hoc Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alabama, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Anti-ERA, 1976-1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arkansas, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "The Best Kept Secret", 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Blatt, Genevieve, 1968-1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bulletins, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Business and Professional Women's Club, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - California, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Carswell, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cartoons, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Civil Rights, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Conformance Project, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Congressional Material, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Congressional Material, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Constitutionality, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - ERA Summit, 1996-2002 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - ERA Workshop, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Essays, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Fact Booklet, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Felton, Walter, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Florida, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Human Rights, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Idaho, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Illinois, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Indiana, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
  - Kennedy Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Ladies Home Journal, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Legal Opinions, 1975, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Legislator Correspondence, 1968-2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Letters Seeking Support, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Mississippi, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - National Women's Conference, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - NOW ERA Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - NOW ERA Convention, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - NOW Legislative Program, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Nevada, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - News Clippings, 1968-2007, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, 1967-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, 1992-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - North Carolina, 1975-1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Notes, 1993-1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Opinions, 1966-1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Pennsylvania ERA, 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Pennsylvania ERA, 1976-1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Pennsylvania ERA Ad-Hoc Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pennsylvania ERA Cases, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
  - Pennsylvania ERA Effects, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Pennsylvania Women's Meeting, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Precedents, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Pro-ERA Organizations, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Projects, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Promotional Material, 1968-1996 (Box 2, Folder 27-28)
  - Promotional Material, 1968-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Publications, 1977, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ratification Attempts, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ratification Attempts, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ratification Attempts, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Research, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Scott, Hugh, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook Material, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Senate Hearings Material, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Senate Hearings Material, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Senate Hearings Material, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Senate Resolution 61, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Seven Year Provision, 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Seven Year Provision, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - South Carolina, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - South Carolina, 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Sponsorship Letters, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - States' Rights, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Strategies, 1969-1979 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Supporting Organizations, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Television/Radio Campaign, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Tennessee, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Testimony, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Testimony Against the ERA, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Tibbs, Marjorie, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Utah, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Virginia, 1973-1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Virginia, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Military Institute, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Wisconsin, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Woman Activist, 1998-2002 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 27th Amendment, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 103rd Congress, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- National Organization of Women, 1966-1998; III.
  Series III consists of material relating to the National Organization for Women (NOW), to which Witter belonged. This series contains newsletters, meeting minutes, conference information, promotional material, memos, and news clippings. The series is divided into three subseries. Subseries 1 is Board of Trustees, Subseries 2 is National, and Subseries 3 is Pennsylvania and Pittsburgh Chapters. These three subseries are each arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Board of Trustees, 1969-1971; 1.
    - Atlanta Meeting, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Chicago Meeting, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Denver Meeting, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Houston Meeting, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Milwaukee Meeting, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - New Orleans Meeting, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Notes, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Pittsburgh Meeting, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - San Francisco Meeting, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Syracuse Meeting, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Washington, DC Meeting, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - National, 1966-1990; 2.
    - Activity, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Activity, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Activity, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Activity, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Activity, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - ACTS, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Bell Telephone, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - By-Laws, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Chapters, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Colgate-Palmolive, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Committee on Administrative Procedures, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Conferences, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Detroit Conference, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Do It Now, 1973-1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Eastern Regional Conference, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Equal Employment Opportunity, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Federal Communications Commission, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Financial Information, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Foundations, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Forms, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Fundraising, 1971-1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Group Ruling, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Heide, Wilma Scott, 1970-1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Legal Defense and Education Fund, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Legal Issues, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Legislation, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Lobbying Information, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Los Angeles Conference, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Members, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Mid-Atlantic Regional Conference, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 1969-1977 (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
    - Newsletters, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Newsletters, 1977-1988 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Notes, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - October 17th Movement, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Organizational Information, 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Press Releases, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Proposed Resolutions, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Publications, 1970-1990 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Public Schools, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Purpose, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Religion, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Reports, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - SMOKE Campaign, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Women and the Law Conference, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Pennsylvania and Pittsburgh Chapters, 1966-1998; 3.
    - Agenda, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Archives, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Bott, Margaret, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - By-Laws, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Committees, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Elections, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Guests, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Leadership Information, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Legislation, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Literature Committee, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Meetings, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Members, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - New Chapter Information, 1966-1971 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Newsletters, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Newsletters, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Notes, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Organizational Information, 1977-1984 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Pennsylvania NOW Times, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Pennsylvania NOW Times, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Pennsylvania NOW Times, 1980-1998 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Pennsylvania State Conference, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Programs, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Promotional Material, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Public Relations, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Reports, 1968-1971 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - South Hills Chapter, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Speakers, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Sports, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Treasurer, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Personal Records, 1970-1992; IV.
  Series IV consists of Witter's personal records. This series includes wills, resumes, and campaign materials. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Campaign Materials, 1970-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Resumes, 1978, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Will and Final Wishes, 1975-1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Women's Issues, 1965-2003; V.
  Series V contains a sampling of information related to women's issues that Witter was interested in but not involved with. The material for this collection was chosen for representation because it was the most common or because it was previously categorized by subject by Witter. This series includes articles, reports, and notes. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Abortion, 1968-1989 (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
  - Affirmative Action, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
  - Articles, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Black Women's Conference, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Bulletins, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Child Care, 1968-1970 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Coalition to Unite Women, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Contract Compliance, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Court Cases, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Custody, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Daly, Mary, 1969-1974 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Divorce, 1970-1972 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Divorce Reform, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Equal Employment, 1971-1989 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Fahnestock, Betty, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Fair Labor Standards Act, 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Family, 1968-1988 (Box 7, Folder 26-27)
  - Federally Employed Women, 1969-1972 (Box 7, Folder 28-29)
  - Friedan, Betty, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Gardner, Jo-Ann Evans, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Hill, Cynthia Judd, 1970-1993 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Hill, Cynthia Judd, 1970-1993 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Homemakers, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - International Women's Year, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Lobbying, 1971-2003 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Maternity Leave, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Medicine, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Menopause, 1970-1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Men's Liberation, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Mental Health, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1971-1999 (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - Music, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Office of Federal Contract Compliance, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Older Women, 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Parent Teacher Association, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Pennsylvania Human Relations Commission, 1966-1974 (Box 8, Folder 17-19)
  - Pennsylvanians for Women's Rights, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Pittsburgh Plate Glass, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Pittsburgh Press, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 22-23)
  - Post Office Employment, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Poverty, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Standby Tax, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Statistics, 1965-1980 (Box 9, Folder 2-4)
  - Swanton, Mary Ellen, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Television and Radio, 1969-1972 (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Women's Equal Rights Coalition, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Women as Property, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Writings, 1955-2003; VI.
  Series VI consists of Witter's personal writings, including material on the women's movement, the ERA, and her own personal reflections. This series contains notebooks, essays, and articles. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Articles about Witter, 1970-1977 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Courage To Be", 1994 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, 1969-1978, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, "The Best Kept Secret of the 20th Century", 1970, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, "Extending Ratification Time for the ERA", 1978 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, "Fear and Fallacy", undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, "Dyer v. Blair", 1976 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, "Fourteenth Amendment Approach", undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, "The Privacy Problem", undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, "Why a Constitutional Amendment?", undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - General Issues, 1955-1967 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Legal Issues, 1972-1982 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Personal Notebooks, 1964-1970 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Personal Notebooks, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Personal Notebooks, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Personal Notebooks, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Personal Notebooks, 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Personal Notebooks, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Personal Notebooks, 1978-1983 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Personal Notebooks, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Personal Notebooks, 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Personal Notebooks, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Personal Notebooks, 1987-1993 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Personal Notebooks, 1994-2003 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Personal Notebooks, undated (Box 10, Folder 7-8)
  - Poems, 1968-1979 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Poems, 1980-1987 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Poems, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Women's Issues, 1968-1972, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Women's Issues, "Oppression in Women", 1970 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Women's Issues, "Pittsburgh Press v. PHRC", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Women's Issues, "Protective Labor Laws", undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Women's Issues, Women's Liberation Sermon, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "Why I Lost the Election", 1970 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Women's Movement Material, 1971-1992; VII.
  Series VII consists of assorted material relating to the women's rights movement, particularly the passage of the ERA. The majority of this material is propaganda and audio/visual material geared to promote recognition of women's issues. This series includes LPs, posters, buttons, jewelry, audio cassettes, and a VHS videotape. The series is arranged by type of material.
  - "Ballad of the ERA/Farmer", 1977 (Box 10, Record 1)
  - "Liberation NOW", undated (Box 10, Record 2)
  - Sexism Board Game, 1971 (Box 10, Volume 1)
  - Equal Rights Amendment Timeline, 1970s (Box 10, Volume 2)
  - ERA Buttons, undated (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
  - ERA Pendant, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - ERA YES Button, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - International Women's Year Badge, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - International Women's Year Jewelry, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Lobbying Buttons, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Community Treatment Centers Talk, 1971 (Box 11, Cassette 1)
  - Equal Rights Amendment Broadcast, 1971 (Box 11, Cassette 2)
  - Goldsmith, Judy, on Women's Rights, 1984 (Box 11, Cassette 3)
  - Schlafly, Phyllis, Testimony Against the ERA, 1973 (Box 11, Cassette 4)
  - Sermon on Women's Rights, 1971 (Box 11, Cassette 5)
  - Women and Religion Broadcast, 1971 (Box 11, Cassette 6)
  - "We Won't Go Back!", 1992 (Box 11, Video 1)